<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writer of code, drinker of seltzer on Home</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writer of code, drinker of seltzer on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:46:28 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Godot Wild Jam 64</title>
      <link>/posts/godot-wild-jam-64/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 15:46:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/godot-wild-jam-64/</guid>
      <description>Godot Wild Jam 64 happened this past month, with the theme Illumination, and I decided to give it a go! This was my 3rd game jam attempt, although this would be my first submitted entry. It&amp;rsquo;s called CandleRun, and you can check it out here.
Along with the main theme, the 3 option &amp;ldquo;wild card&amp;rdquo; themes were &amp;ldquo;white out/ freezing out&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;blood is fuel&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;trash everywhere&amp;rdquo;.
Design Process I originally planned on a completely different game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new space for snake</title>
      <link>/posts/micro-snake-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 14:01:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/micro-snake-3/</guid>
      <description>Oh yeah. We&amp;rsquo;re rollin now. Bug fixes and new state trigger logic!
Diagonal movement bug Had to change the movement vector code to fix a bug that would allow the player to move in diagonals&amp;hellip; which kind of breaks the whole rule set of Snake now doesn&amp;rsquo;t it. This is because the Input.get_vector() func will create a vector based on all inputs it recieves. Good for some games like top down 2d or 3d games, not good for snake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving snake an apple</title>
      <link>/posts/micro-snake-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 10:57:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/micro-snake-2/</guid>
      <description>Before tackling any new features, I wanted to make sure I atleast had a super bare minimum state management system in place. And a new beta for Godot 4 is out and I get to use a new (very minor) enhancement :D
Managing state This is pretty much as simple as you can get, which I think fits for the tiny scope of this project. For now this is what that looks like</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Godot 4 Tilemaps via Snake</title>
      <link>/posts/godot-4-tilemaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 17:29:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/godot-4-tilemaps/</guid>
      <description>With Godot 4 now in beta, I&amp;rsquo;ve been starting to mess around with the new kit. And although there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of really exciting 3d features coming to Godot 4, the 2d space is a bit more in my wheelhouse for now, as I continue to learn the engine.
One new feature I am looking forward to using in Godot 4 2d is the new TileMap node updates. To get myself farmiliar with the new TileMap api, I wanted a project that would let me dip my toes into this node, but I also wanted a project that had a small scope and ideally I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to think up rules or functionality from scratch.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
